(647) 679-8032

Alireza Torabian

☑ torabian@yorku.ca

torabian.alireza@gmail.com Graduate Student / Experienced in Machine Learning

% www.eecs.yorku.ca/ torabian/ 1997alireza **in** alireza-torabian

As a computer science graduate student at York University, I am focusing my research on the field of machine learning calibration. With a strong foundation in mathematics, I have a comprehensive understanding of the theories and principles behind machine learning. I have completed a number of projects in various areas, including deep learning, computer vision, adversarial machine learning, and natural language processing.

EDUCATION

York University 2021-2023 (Expected)

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Advised by Ruth Urner, GPA: A+

Toronto, Canada

Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic)

2015-2020

B.Sc. in Computer (Software) Engineering, Advised by Saeedeh Momtazi, GPA: 3.9/4 (In the top 10%)

Tehran, Iran

Thesis: Design and Implementation of a Persian Automatic Question Answering System

EXPERIENCE

Jan. 2021 - Present York University

Machine learning researcher

Toronto, Canada

Explored desirable properties of calibration models as well as evaluation metrics and analyzed their feasibility and correspondences.

National University of Singapore, Data Privacy and Trustworthy Machine Learning Research Lab Computer vision researcher (Github repo)

Jul. 2019 - Sep. 2019 Singapore

• Developed a plugin that will obscure images in order to increase privacy that achieved 35% success rate.

- Performed a black-box adversarial attack on facial recognition using projected gradient descent with momentum in latent space of FaceNet.
- In face detection attack, the intersection of the detected face and the original face is minimized using PGD.
- Image augmentations are used to apply the attacks on black-box models.

Diaalog Jul. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Deep learning R&D intern

Tehran, Iran

Tehran, Iran

- Developed a Persian question answering system in Python Tensorflow.
- · Using a seq2seq model or clustering by LDA.

Amirkabir University of Technology, Cognitive Robotics Lab

Oct. 2016 - Sep. 2017

Research Assistant

- Object detection task is performed to detect victims using YOLO model.
- Developed an autonomous exploration algorithm and path planner for robots to help them explore a map simultaneously.

SKILLS

Python, Java, C++, JavaScript Languages

Machine learning TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, NLTK, Scipy, JAX, OpenCV

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Other Tools Git, Unix shell, Jupyter

PROJECTS

Alternative Actor and Co-Star Suggestion Using a Graph Autoencoder Model

Apr. 2021

- Applied a graph autoencoder to a network of actors using Keras in Python achieved 99.46% accuracy on reconstruction the graph. Github repo
- An alternative actor is found by searching the latent space using a K-d tree.
- A co-star is suggested according to the predicted weights from an autoencoder model.

Persian Question Answering System

Aug. 2020

Developed a question answering system using a knowledge-base in Python.

Github repo

SVM and CNN classification models used to classify questions achieved 96% accuracy and F1-score of 92.7%.

Optimization Coursework

Jul. 2019

• Implemented unconstrained and constrained optimizations, such as line search, trust region, and log barrier for convex problems. Github repo

Dec. 2018 Github repo

• Implemented a seq2seq model with an attention mechanism, using Tensorflow in Python.

Honors and Awards

Neural Dialogue System

York University Fellowship, C\$62,500 for my master's studies	2021-2022
Second Place in the rescue simulation virtual robot league at RoboCup in Nagoya, Japan	2017
Ranked top 0.5% in nationwide Iranian university entrance exam among 180,000 participants	2015
Member of National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents (NODET)	2011-2015